# **TALEN BENTLEY-MICHAUD**

North Vancouver, British Columbia 604-379-3134 | talen@bentleym<u>ichaud.ca</u>

A graduate of the Bachelor of Motion Picture Arts program at Capilano University, with five years of experience as an editor and videographer a variety of scripted and non-scripted projects, combining skills in cinematography, video editing, motion design, and project management. Through his experience as a freelance editor and filmmaker, he has striven to deepen and strengthen his craft at every turn. Talen always seeks to push creative boundaries by telling fresh and compelling stories through film.

# **Production Credits**

St. Paul's Lights of Hope 2024	Editor & Animator	2024	Promotional
No Strings Attached	Editor	2024	Short
Hats Off	Editor	2024	Short
Celista	Editor	2024	Short
My Lily	Editor	2024	Short
St. Paul's Lights of Hope 2023	Editor & Animator	2023	Promotional
Meet Ole Cypress	Editor	2023	Doc Short
The End of Attention	Editor	2023	Short
Hornby Island Sailing Promo	Editor	2023	Promotional
The Four Children	Editor	2023	Short
Liberte	Director	2023	Short
Doppel4U	Assistant Editor	2023	Short
I.P.A	Editor	2022	Short
Dear Frances	Editor	2022	Short
Hit Me with Your Best Shot	Editor	2021	Short
		1	

# **Education**

#### **Bachelor of Motion Picture Arts**

Capilano University, North Vancouver, British Columbia

Graduated With Distinction May 2024

- Full technical knowledge of cinema cameras, lenses, and lighting equipment
- Instruction and experience in cinematography and directing
- Experience with production management
- Extensive experience with industry standard post-production software and organizational tools.

### **Work Experience**

#### **Editor & Animator**

St. Paul's Light's of Hope

2023 & 2024

- Designed, animated, and edited video for the Lights of Hope live performance.
- Liaised with fellow team members and St. Paul's staff to design a cohesive and effective show.
- Managed a large inventory of assets and documents during the production process.
- Presented in a timely manner completed versions, maintaining strong version control.

#### Freelance Video Producer

Various Clients

2020 - Present

- Capture, collect, backup, and organize project media in a timely fashion, maintaining good data integrity standards.
- Edit video content, which may include graphics, sound, or colour correction.
- Incorporated client revisions quickly and effectively.

### **Marketing Video Editor**

Associated Engineering - Practicum Placement

2023

- Edited marketing video content for promotional, training, and documenting purposes.
- Designed motion graphics for use in promotional video material.
- Discussed design and marketing strategies with the business development team.

### Media Manager

Highlands United Church

2020 - Present

- Manage and lead tech crew for church services, rentals, and all other media needs.
- Work closely with church leadership to address concerns and plan for future growth.
- Maintain and expand church equipment.
- Film and edit church video media for use in services, or for promotional purposes.

#### Barista

Delany's Coffee House

2024 - Present

- Offer excellent customer service, fulfilling all orders and requests quickly and accurately.
- Engage customers at all times, presenting a warm and positive attitude for all patrons.
- Make beverages speedily, paying careful attention to recipe accuracy and quality control.
- Utilize strong organizational skills to manage the stresses of a public-facing work environment.

# **Technical Skills**

Video Production	Audio Production	Hardware	Photo & Graphics
AVID Media Composer	Avid Protools	Canon Cinema Line	Adobe Photoshop
Premiere Pro	Adobe Audition	RED Cinema Cameras	Adobe Illustrator
After Effects		ARRI Alexa	Adobe Lightroom
Davinci Resolve			